Hansdeep (Hans)

Phone: 042-66-76567, South East, Melbourne 3177 **Online portfolio-CV**: https://www.hansdeep.pro

ABOUT ME

Over 4 years in Leadership and Over 14 Years of experience in Software Development including Web - Angular, MVC, ASP.net, .NET Framework, Cloud - AZURE Android, IOS development. Strong hold on current technologies, up for grabs into upcoming ones.

Team management - Strategic planning - Decision making - Problem solving

SKILLS

- Building architecture around Microservices.
- Building own in-house .net Packages and Angular Libraries.
- Progressive-Web-Application which can be installed on Android and iOS devices, on all kinds of mobile phones, tablets and computers.
- Front-end responsive design based upon Google's Material design.
- C# clean code as programming language as back-end logic with Entity Framework. .net Factory pattern for dependency injection.
- Ability to be dependent upon by teammates and stake holders.
- Creation of Azure DevOps pipelines for CI/CD deployments.
- Extensive experience in Azure portal resources.
- Strong hold on .Net 6 + Web API applications.
- Strong hold on Angular 13 + /Typescript development.
- Token based and OpenID connect OAuth Authentications/Authorizations.
- Successful Integration with 3rd party applications example (Instructure, Microsoft 365 CRM, Qlik Sense server etc.)
- Strong hold on Back-end strategic design methodologies with MVC/MVVM Approach and Form based web applications (ASP.net).
- Strong hold on Front-end pixel perfect balanced interactive userinterface design, responsive on all screens and adapted for all devices e.g., Apple and Windows, with use of latest HTML5, CSS3, SASS
- JavaScript and Typescript (Angular)
- Strong hold on Relational Database management. Expert in running SQL queries.
- GitHub for repository update for version control.
- Quick learner I use latest web technologies and easily adapt to the new upcoming technologies.
- Excellent communication including the ability to distil technical details into easy human terms.

EXPERIENCE

LEAD, SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT

Independent Schools Victoria

Oct 2022 -Current

- I am proud to have deployed our new isEducation platform for Independent Schools Victoria which is built on the latest technologies listed in my skill set. Taking lead on project development https://education.is.vic.edu.au
- Development of in-house Angular TypeScript Libraries and .net NuGet packages.
- Managing team of developers and cloud engineers for building solutions for our schools/organisations.
- Interactions with Stakeholder and Non-Technical people on regular bases.
- Certificate in Agile Project Management.
- Taking lead on transitioning isEducation Suite from OLD MVC "Monolithic architecture" into NEW Angular PWA-Responsive (latest) front end and .net (latest) API. "Micro-services architecture"
- isEducation suite is built upon Azure B2C Tenant, OAuth2.0
 Authentication/Authorization. Where isEducation acts as an OAuth 2.0 server. Suite apps act as client applications.
- Taking lead on setting up Eco-System (Environments -Dev/UAT/Staging/Production) for isEducation suite applications.
- Setting up environment also includes creating Resources in Azure Portal and deploying website on relevant URLs.
- Building pipelines per isEducation Suite App per environment for CI/CD
- Collaborating with team of developers and cloud engineers for building solutions for our schools.
- Weekly scrum for monitoring on-going development and adhering to task deadlines.
- isEducation suite includes various products such as isLearn, isAnalyse, isConnect, isCommunicate, isRecruit, isPodcast, isArtwork
- API Integration with 3rd party tool (Qlik Sense Analytics)
- Maintenance of OLD isEducation suite built on Blazor Web Assembly from Microsoft and .net Framework.
- Development and version release of Xamarin Android Apps (isCommunicate) on Google Play

EXPERIENCE

SENIOR DEVELOPER (Full Stack)

ComputerShare

May 2020 -Sept 2022

- Working at ComputerShare's Utility department.
- Collaborating with a team of Senior developers and Solutions architect building solutions for our clients.
- Ongoing discussion with business analysts to keep with the scope of projects.
- Admin dashboards with charts and analytics data.
- Our systems provide billing services for Energy Industry (Gas, Electricity and Water) for clients such as SimplyEnergy, EnergyAustralia, UnityWater, HunterWater + (13 more)
- Ours is a Progressive Web App built on Angular 13, .net 6, C#
- We also built apps for Our Client's Field Sales which generally includes bill comparison.

- Ongoing support and monitoring of our systems.
- We use our own package libraries (Angular and .net)
- Continuous Integration and Deployment pipelines on Azure

EXPERIENCE

FULL STACK .NET DEVELOPER

CPM Australia

Jan 2019 -April 2020

- Working alongside an established team of developers, interaction with marketing teams, graphic designers and business analytics team.
- Revamped Entire UI/UX Interface from scratch for all the applications currently being used at CPM which includes Mobile Apps.
- Developed CRM to manage in-bound calls for in-house **LOreal** CRM portal.
- Currently developing CRM for LOreal employees.
- Developed CRM features for Optus CRM, American Express, Subaru, AGL Gas, Saputo.
- Ongoing monitoring of servers, reporting and working along with Infrastructure team.
- Development of Mobile (iOS/Android) Apps with the use of Apache Cordova tools
- Expertise in web development using MVC and ASP.net, JavaScript/jQuery and other JavaScript libraries.
- Experience in .Net Core and Angular Apps.
- Working in an Agile Scrum based environment.
- Expert in SQL queries for update inserts and for a generation of reports.
- Providing ongoing support to the AMEX sales rep representatives.
- Angular Dashboards with .Net Core and live updates.
- Development of prototype UI / Projects to present to the stakeholders for future clients.
- Relational database designs, new and upgrading existing databases.

FULL STACK .NET DEVELOPER/DIRECTOR (NZ)

ExpertSystems Ltd

Sept 2013 -July 2018

- Development of various websites projects hosted on windows hosting servers.
- Responsible for client interactions, people management, including management of timelines for roll outs, and providing them with performance feedback.
- Implementing security role-based authorization and authentication.
- Developed an online roster system, with duty cards for NZ Bus.
 Reference Available.
- Web design from scratch. Use of Bootstrap and HTML5/CSS3 tools for fast-paced development.
- Graphic designing of Jerseys, Logos, Business cards, Posters, Wine bottle branding, Commercial advertisement designing for Magazine.
- 3-D Web-GL development to render Architecture Design with the use of Three.js, CSS3, HTML5

Software development for outlined work, maintain and monitor software functionality, design and architecture.

Website development/maintenance with logo/apparel design for the following: - (NZ)

Team Sports Ltd (Feb 2010 to Sept > Team Sports is a Licensed distributor for Adidas gear and other sports goods.

Designed posters, Caps and maintaining company website

2010) Silver Fern

> Apparel design, website maintenance.

Sports Ltd

(Jan 2009 to April 2009)

My Biz Websites > Sports club websites development, support and Logo design

Ltd

(Feb 2008 to Jan 2009)

BiscoPro Ltd (July 2007 to Oct 2007)

> During Study, developed a plugin for Google SketchUp software using Ruby on rails programming language and Google SketchUp API.

EDUCATION

A.I.S. St Helens **Enterprise Award** Graduate diploma in information technology (LEVEL-7), 10/2007 For all-round excellence, determination to succeed and general team spirit.

Punjab University

Technical Bachelor's degree of Computer Science, 9/2006

Cyber Security

Holmesglen institute Chadstone. Melbourne

Referees are available on request